PIOTR MIGDAŁ, PHD

deep learning specialist, technical visionary & leader

@ pmigdal@gmail.com

remote & Warsaw, Poland

p.migdal.pl

y pmigdal

in piotrmigdal

stared



I am open to ambitious challenges combining AI with the end-user experience.

I would happily consider industries such as medtech, biotech, and user-centric AI. Ideal roles include data science tech lead, head of Al, technical product manager, and CTO.

EXPERIENCE

co-founder & CTO

Quantum Flytrap

2020 - 2022

- Singapore & Warsaw, Poland
- A startup delivering quantum computing to businesses through an accessible IDE.
- Raised a VC-backed pre-seed round.
- Led the development of a state-of-the-art numerical engine, which performs quantum computation in real-time in the browser.
- Delivered a web-based quantum computing interface to Pasgal, a leading quantum hardware manufacturer - a paying customer.
- Created Virtual Lab, an interactive simulation of entangled photons, used at Stanford and Oxford universities.
- Nominated to the 27th Webby Awards in the Science category, alongside NASA and OpenAI websites.
- Key tech: TypeScript, Vue, Rust, WASM, quantum computing.

Al researcher

ECC Games

2020 - 2021

- Warsaw, Poland
- Designed and led implementation of deep learning models for simulating racing car physics & unsupervised image segmentation.
- Authored a publication "Level generation and style enhancement deep learning for game development overview".
- Key tech: Python, PyTorch.

machine and deep learning consulting independent

2015 - 2019

- US, Europe
- Trainings and consulting for: deepsense.ai, Intel, Nielsen, Samsung Research, and BCG.
- Key tech: Python, Jupyter Notebook, Scikit Learn, PyTorch, Keras.

data science and data viz freelancing independent

2014 - 2015

- remote & Warsaw, Poland
- Selected clients: Data4Cure, Startup Compass, Laboratorium EE.
- Key tech: Python, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, JavaScript, D3.js.



LIFE PHILOSOPHY

"You live as long as you learn."

BEYOND WORK

livelossplot

Developed a popular Python library for visualizing deep learning model training, with over 1.5M installations.



Data Science PL

Created the largest data science community in Poland - over 20k members.



RSI & IPhO

Alumnus of the MIT Research Science Institute, an International Physics Olympiad bronze medalist.



Popularity

Over 15 of my projects and writings have been featured on the Hacker News front page.



Broad interests 19 research publications in physics, mathematical psychology, educational games, and data visualization.

LANGUAGES

Polish

English

EDUCATION

PhD in quantum optics theory **ICFO - The Institute of Photonic Sciences**

- **2011 2014**
- Castelldefels, Spain
- Maciej Lewenstein's group.
- Reviewed by Seth Lloyd (MIT).

MSc in physics **University of Warsaw**

2005 - 2011

Warsaw, Poland

BSc in mathematics **University of Warsaw**

2005 - 2009

Warsaw, Poland